<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Periodic controller | JuliaReach</title>
    <link>https://juliareach.github.io/tag/periodic-controller/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://juliareach.github.io/tag/periodic-controller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Periodic controller</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 JuliaReach Developers</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://juliareach.github.io/media/JuliaReach_ISOLOGO_vertical.jpg</url>
      <title>Periodic controller</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/tag/periodic-controller/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient reachability analysis of parametric linear hybrid systems with time-triggered transitions</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/timetrigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/timetrigger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient reachability analysis of parametric linear hybrid systems with time-triggered transitions.&lt;/strong&gt; Marcelo Forets, Daniel Freire, Christian Schilling, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.12325&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv: 2006.12325&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented in MEMOCODE&#39;20: &lt;a href=&#34;https://iitjammu.ac.in/conferences/memocode2020/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;18th ACM-IEEE International Conference on Formal Methods and Models for System Design
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficiently handling time-triggered and possibly nondeterministic switches for hybrid systems
reachability is a challenging task. In this paper we focus on periodically controlled systems
with fast-switching controller dynamics, which often require simulation time scales of the order
of nanoseconds. Accurate set-based computations for such systems with relatively large time
horizons are expensive due to the accumulation of errors in the discrete transitions.
We present an approach based on conservative set-based enclosure of the dynamics that can handle systems
with uncertain parameters and inputs. We demonstrate our algorithm on the plant model of an
experimental electro-mechanical braking system with periodic controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timed systems play an important role in modeling and analyzing cyber-physical systems.
In this work we consider a class of hybrid-automaton models with continuous dynamics and time-triggered discrete events following a periodic clock.
We propose a reachability framework to compute an overapproximation of the states reachable by such systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conventional techniques tightly integrate the computation of the continuous behavior and the discrete events.
Our approach allows to separate these concerns for the model class considered here, which simplifies
the analysis drastically in practice and allows us to plug in any reachability algorithm from the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a case study, we consider a parametric model of a cyber-physical system consisting of an experimental
electro-mechanical brake and a software-implemented periodic controller.
The model was originally described in earlier work by Strathmann and Oehlerking where the
authors developed a simplified version of a nonlinear system.
The model is representative of real challenges in the automotive industry and allows the application of formal methods during development.
Computing the reachable states for this simplified model takes twelve hours using the previous
approach, and less than a minute with our approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper makes the following original contributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present an efficient algorithm for deterministic periodic time-triggered hybrid systems with &lt;strong&gt;uncertain parameters&lt;/strong&gt; of the system dynamics or the initial conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We extend the algorithm to the more difficult and new scenario of &lt;strong&gt;nondeterministic periodic&lt;/strong&gt; discrete switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate the &lt;strong&gt;efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; of our algorithm on a model of an electro-mechanical brake system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation slides (pdf) are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JuliaReach/JuliaReach-website/tree/master/Talks/EMBrake_MEMOCODE20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short video for MEMOCODE&#39;20 is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n9ZNZmL1tlw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{forets2020efficient,
  title={Efficient reachability analysis of parametric linear hybrid systems with time-triggered transitions},
  author={Forets, Marcelo and Freire, Daniel and Schilling, Christian},
  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2006.12325},
  year={2020}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JuliaReach: a Toolbox for Set-Based Reachability</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/juliareachtoolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/juliareachtoolbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JuliaReach: a Toolbox for Set-Based Reachability.&lt;/strong&gt; Sergiy Bogomolov, Marcelo Forets, Goran Frehse, Kostiantyn Potomkin, Christian Schilling. Published in Proceedings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://hscc2019.eecs.umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HSCC&#39;19&lt;/a&gt;: 22nd ACM International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (HSCC&#39;19), see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3311804&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACM link here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.10736&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Get pdf from arXiv: 1901.10736&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present JuliaReach, a toolbox for set-based
reachability analysis of dynamical systems.
JuliaReach consists of two main packages: Reachability, containing implementations
of reachability algorithms for continuous
and hybrid systems, and LazySets, a
standalone library that implements
state-of-the-art algorithms for calculus
with convex sets. The library offers both
concrete and lazy set representations, where
the latter stands for the ability to delay
set computations until they are needed. The
choice of the programming language Julia and
the accompanying documentation of our
toolbox allow researchers to easily translate
set-based algorithms from mathematics to
software in a platform-independent way,
while achieving runtime performance that
is comparable to statically compiled languages.
Combining lazy operations in high dimensions
and explicit computations in low dimensions,
JuliaReach can be applied to solve complex,
large-scale problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{bogomolov2019juliareach,
  title={JuliaReach: a toolbox for set-based reachability},
  author={Bogomolov, Sergiy and Forets, Marcelo and Frehse, Goran and Potomkin, Kostiantyn and Schilling, Christian},
  booktitle={Proceedings of the 22nd ACM International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control},
  pages={39--44},
  year={2019}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reach Set Approximation through Decomposition with Low-dimensional Sets and High-dimensional Matrices</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/bffpsv18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/bffpsv18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach Set Approximation through Decomposition with Low-dimensional Sets and High-dimensional Matrices.&lt;/strong&gt; Sergiy Bogomolov, Marcelo Forets, Goran Frehse, Frédéric Viry, Andreas Podelski and Christian Schilling (2018) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hscc2018.deib.polimi.it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HSCC&#39;18&lt;/a&gt; Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control: 41–50. See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3178126.3178128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ACM Digital Library link&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.09526&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv: 1801.09526&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximating the set of reachable states of a dynamical system is an
algorithmic yet mathematically rigorous way to reason about its safety.
Although progress has been made in the development of efficient algorithms
for affine dynamical systems, available algorithms still lack scalability
to ensure their wide adoption in the industrial setting. While modern
linear algebra packages are efficient for matrices with tens of thousands
of dimensions, set-based image computations are limited to a few hundred.
We propose to decompose reach set computations such that set operations
are performed in low dimensions, while matrix operations like exponentiation
are carried out in the full dimension. Our method is applicable both in dense
and discrete-time settings. For a set of standard benchmarks, it shows a
speed-up of up to two orders of magnitude compared to the respective
state-of-the-art tools, with only modest losses in accuracy.
For the dense-time case, we show an experiment with more than 10,000
variables, roughly two orders of magnitude higher than possible with previous
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a new method to solve the reachability
problem for affine dynamical systems with nondeterministic inputs
and experimentally show that it is highly scalable under modest
loss of accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More precisely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We provide a new decomposition approach to solve the set-based recurrence:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
\mathcal{X}(k+1) = \Phi \mathcal{X}(k) \oplus \mathcal{V}(k),\qquad k = 0, 1,\ldots, N
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze the approximation error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We address both the dense time and the discrete time reach-
ability problem for general linear time-invariant systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We implement our approach efficiently and demonstrate its
scalability on real engineering benchmarks. The tool, source
code, and benchmark scripts are publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{bogomolov2018reach,
  title={Reach set approximation through decomposition with low-dimensional sets and high-dimensional matrices},
  author={Bogomolov, Sergiy and Forets, Marcelo and Frehse, Goran and Viry, Fr{\&#39;e}d{\&#39;e}ric and Podelski, Andreas and Schilling, Christian},
  booktitle={Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (part of CPS Week)},
  pages={41--50},
  year={2018}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
