<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ARCH-COMP | JuliaReach</title>
    <link>https://juliareach.github.io/tag/arch-comp/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://juliareach.github.io/tag/arch-comp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ARCH-COMP</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 JuliaReach Developers</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://juliareach.github.io/media/JuliaReach_ISOLOGO_vertical.jpg</url>
      <title>ARCH-COMP</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/tag/arch-comp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Result Award: Applied Verification for Continuous and Hybrid Systems 2020</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/post/archcomp20_prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/post/archcomp20_prize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prize-announcement&#34;&gt;Prize announcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cps-vo.org/node/69589&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ARCH 2020 Best Result Award&lt;/a&gt; goes to Luis Benet, Marcelo Forets, Daniel Freire, David P. Sanders, and Christian Schilling (in alphabetical order) for their verification tool JuliaReach. The award comes with a 500 Euro prize. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resolution&#34;&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will give the prize to Sebastian (&lt;code&gt;@sebastianguadalupe&lt;/code&gt;), a Uruguayan
undergraduate student who collabored with us on the Julia Seasons of Contributions 2020 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian will work on zonotope-based methods applied to hybrid systems.
He will be writing a tool for reachability analysis of neural-network controlled systems
to leverage on the JuliaReach ecosystem and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sisl/NeuralVerification.jl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sisl/NeuralVerification.jl&lt;/a&gt;
from the Stanford Intelligent Systems Laboratory library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCH-COMP19 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp19_aff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp19_aff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARCH-COMP19 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt; Matthias Althoff, Stanley Bak, Marcelo Forets, Goran Frehse, Niklas Kochdumper, Rajarshi Ray, Christian Schilling and Stefan Schupp (2019) ARCH19. 6th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems, vol 61, pages 14&amp;ndash;40 &lt;a href=&#34;https://easychair.org/publications/paper/1gbP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;doi: 10.29007/bj1w&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp20_aff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp20_aff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt;
Matthias Althoff, Stanley Bak, Zongnan Bao, Marcelo Forets, Daniel Freire, Goran Frehse, Niklas
Kochdumper, Yangge Li, Sayan Mitra, Rajarshi Ray, Christian Schilling, Stefan Schupp, and Mark
Wetzlinger (2020) ARCH20. 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and
Hybrid Systems. 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems
(ARCH20), vol 74, pages 16&amp;ndash;48. &lt;a href=&#34;https://easychair.org/publications/paper/DRpS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.29007/7dt2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present the results of the ARCH 2020
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://cps-vo.org/group/ARCH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Workshop on Applied Verification for Continuous and Hybrid Systems&lt;/a&gt; friendly
competition for formal verification of continuous and hybrid systems with linear continuous dynamics.
In its fourth edition, eight tools have been applied to solve eight different benchmark problems in the
category for linear continuous dynamics (in alphabetical order): CORA, C2E2, HyDRA, Hylaa, Hylaa-Continuous,
JuliaReach, SpaceEx, and XSpeed. This report is a snapshot of the current landscape of tools and the types of
benchmarks they are particularly suited for. Due to the diversity of problems, we are not ranking tools,
yet the presented results provide one of the most complete assessments of tools for the safety verification
of continuous and hybrid systems with linear continuous dynamics up to this date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider the verification of hybrid systems (i.e., mixed discrete/continuous systems) with linear continuous dynamics
$$
\dot{x}(t) = Ax(t) + Bu(t),
$$
where $A \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times n}$, $x \in \mathbb{R}^n$, $B \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times m}$, and $u \in \mathbb{R}^m$. For all results reported by each participant, we have run an independent repeatability evaluation. To establish further trustworthiness of the results, the code with which the results have been obtained is publicly available &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/goranf/ARCH-COMP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
The selection of the benchmarks has been conducted within the forum of the ARCH website
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://cps-vo.org/group/ARCH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), which is visible for registered users and
registration is open to anybody. All tools presented in this report use some form of
reachability analysis. This, however, is not a constraint set by the organizers of the friendly competition. We hope to encourage further tool developers to showcase their results in future editions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{ARCH20:ARCH_COMP20_Category_Report_Continuous,
  author    = {Matthias Althoff and Stanley Bak and Zongnan Bao and Marcelo Forets and Goran Frehse and Daniel Freire and Niklas Kochdumper and Yangge Li and Sayan Mitra and Rajarshi Ray and Christian Schilling and Stefan Schupp and Mark Wetzlinger},
  title     = {ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics},
  booktitle = {ARCH20. 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems (ARCH20)},
  editor    = {Goran Frehse and Matthias Althoff},
  series    = {EPiC Series in Computing},
  volume    = {74},
  pages     = {16--48},
  year      = {2020},
  publisher = {EasyChair},
  bibsource = {EasyChair, https://easychair.org},
  issn      = {2398-7340},
  url       = {https://easychair.org/publications/paper/DRpS},
  doi       = {10.29007/7dt2}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Nonlinear Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp20_nln/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp20_nln/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Nonlinear Dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt; Luca Geretti, Julien Alexandre dit Sandretto, Matthias Althoff, Luis Benet, Alexandre Chapoutot, Xin Chen, Pieter Collins, Marcelo Forets, Daniel Freire, Fabian Immler, Niklas Kochdumper, David P. Sanders and Christian
Schilling (2020) ARCH20. To appear in 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems. 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems (ARCH20), vol 74, pages 49&amp;ndash;75. &lt;a href=&#34;https://easychair.org/publications/paper/nrdD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.29007/zkf6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present the results of a friendly competition for formal verification of continuous and hybrid
systems with nonlinear continuous dynamics. The friendly competition took place as part of the
workshop Applied Verification for Continuous and Hybrid Systems (ARCH) in 2020. This year, 6 tools
Ariadne, CORA, DynIbex, Flow*, Isabelle/HOL, and JuliaReach (in alphabetic order) participated.
These tools are applied to solve reachability analysis problems on six benchmark problems, two of them
featuring hybrid dynamics. We do not rank the tools based on the results, but show the current status
and discover the potential advantages of different tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we summarize the results of the fourth ARCH friendly competition on the
reachability analysis of continuous and hybrid systems with nonlinear dynamics. Given a system
defined by a nonlinear Ordinary Differential Equation (ODE) $\dot{x} = f(x, t)$ along with an initial
condition $x \in X_0$, we apply the participating tools to prove properties of the state reachable set
in a bounded time horizon. The techniques for solving such a problem are usually very sensitive
to not only the nonlinearity of the dynamics but also the size of the initial set. This is also one
of the main reasons why most of the tools require quite a lot of computational parameters.
In this report, 6 tools Ariadne, CORA, DynIbex, Flow*, Isabelle/HOL, and JuliaReach
participated in solving problems defined on four continuous and two hybrid benchmarks. The
continuous benchmarks are the Production-Destruction system, the Coupled Van der Pol os-
cillator, the Laub-Loomis model, and a controlled Quadrotor model. The hybrid benchmarks
model a Lotka-Volterra system with a Tangential Crossing, and a Space Rendezvous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2020 edition of the competition we introduced two new benchmarks: the Production-
Destruction system and the Lotka-Volterra system with tangential crossing. The former is a
continuous system aimed at identifying the stability of integration schemes. The latter intro-
duces nonlinear guards and in particular tangential crossings. In addition, we extended the van
der Pol oscillator to two coupled oscillators, introduced nondeterministic crossing in the Space
Rendezvous system and performed some input sensitivity analysis for the Quadrotor system.
The Laub-Loomis benchmark was not modified, in order to perform a direct comparison with
results from the previous year (since the participants are the same).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{ARCH20:ARCH_COMP20_Category_Report_Continuous,
  author    = {Luca Geretti and Julien Alexandre Dit Sandretto and Matthias Althoff and Luis Benet and Alexandre Chapoutot and Xin Chen and Pieter Collins and Marcelo Forets and Daniel Freire and Fabian Immler and Niklas Kochdumper and David P. Sanders and Christian Schilling},
  title     = {ARCH-COMP20 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Nonlinear Dynamics},
  booktitle = {ARCH20. 7th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems (ARCH20)},
  editor    = {Goran Frehse and Matthias Althoff},
  series    = {EPiC Series in Computing},
  volume    = {74},
  pages     = {49--75},
  year      = {2020},
  publisher = {EasyChair},
  bibsource = {EasyChair, https://easychair.org},
  issn      = {2398-7340},
  url       = {https://easychair.org/publications/paper/nrdD},
  doi       = {10.29007/zkf6}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCH-COMP19 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Nonlinear Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp19_nln/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp19_nln/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARCH-COMP19 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Nonlinear Dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt;
Fabian Immler, Matthias Althoff, Luis Benet,
Alexandre Chapoutot, Xin Chen, Marcelo Forets,
Luca Geretti, Niklas Kochdumper,
David P. Sanders and Christian Schilling (2019)
ARCH19. 6th International Workshop on Applied
Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems,
vol 61, pages 41&amp;ndash;61
&lt;a href=&#34;https://easychair.org/publications/paper/1gbP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;doi: 10.29007/bj1w&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCH-COMP18 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp18_aff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliareach.github.io/project/archcomp18_aff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARCH-COMP18 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt;
Matthias Althoff, Stanley Bak, Xin Chen, Chuchu Fan, Marcelo Forets, Goran Frehse,
Niklas Kochdumper, Yangge Li, Sayan Mitra, Rajarshi Ray, Christian Schilling and Stefan Schupp (2018) ARCH18.
5th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems, 54: 23–52.
doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.29007/73mb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.29007/73mb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report presents the results of a friendly competition for formal verification of continuous
and hybrid systems with linear continuous dynamics. The friendly competition took place as part
of the workshop Applied Verification for Continuous and Hybrid Systems (ARCH) in 2018.
In its second edition, 9 tools have been applied to solve six different benchmark problems
in the category for linear continuous dynamics (in alphabetical order): CORA, CORA/SX, C2E2,
Flow*, HyDRA, Hylaa, Hylaa-Continuous, JuliaReach, SpaceEx, and XSpeed.
This report is a snapshot of the current landscape of tools and the types of benchmarks
they are particularly suited for. Due to the diversity of problems, we are not ranking tools,
yet the presented results probably provide the most complete assessment of tools for
the safety verification of continuous and hybrid systems with linear continuous dynamics up to this date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report summarizes results obtained in the 2018 friendly competition of the ARCH
workshop for verifying hybrid systems with linear continuous dynamics
$$
\dot{x}(t) = Ax(t) + Bu(t),
$$
where $A \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times n}$, $x \in \mathbb{R}^n$, $B \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times m}$, and $u \in \mathbb{R}^m$.
Participating tools are summarized in
Sec. 2. The results of our selected benchmark problems are shown in Sec. 3 and are obtained
on the tool developers’ own machines. Thus, one has to factor in the computational power of
the processors used, summarized in Appendix A, as well as the efficiency of the programming
language of the tools.
The goal of the friendly competition is not to rank the results, but rather to present the
landscape of existing solutions in a breadth that is not possible with scientific publications in
classical venues. Such publications would typically require the presentation of novel techniques,
while this report showcases the current state-of-the-art tools. For all results reported by each
participant, we have run an independent repeatability evaluation.
The selection of the benchmarks has been conducted within the forum of the ARCH website
(&lt;a href=&#34;cps-vo.org/group/ARCH&#34;&gt;cps-vo.org/group/ARCH&lt;/a&gt;), which is visible for registered users
and registration is open for anybody. All tools presented in this report use some form
of reachability analysis. This, however, is not a constraint set by the organizers of
the friendly competition. We hope to encourage further tool developers to showcase
their results in future editions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cite&#34;&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{ARCH18:ARCH_COMP18_Category_Report_Continuous,
  author    = {Matthias Althoff and Stanley Bak and Xin Chen and Chuchu Fan and Marcelo Forets and Goran Frehse and Niklas Kochdumper and Yangge Li and Sayan Mitra and Rajarshi Ray and Christian Schilling and Stefan Schupp},
  title     = {ARCH-COMP18 Category Report: Continuous and Hybrid Systems with Linear Continuous Dynamics},
  booktitle = {ARCH18. 5th International Workshop on Applied Verification of Continuous and Hybrid Systems},
  editor    = {Goran Frehse},
  series    = {EPiC Series in Computing},
  volume    = {54},
  pages     = {23--52},
  year      = {2018},
  publisher = {EasyChair},
  bibsource = {EasyChair, https://easychair.org},
  issn      = {2398-7340},
  url       = {https://easychair.org/publications/paper/4cGr},
  doi       = {10.29007/73mb}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
